现在, 戴尔, 仔细听好了.
Now, Dale, listen carefully.
该你走了.
lt's your move.
请你用心去走好每一步,
你会的吧?
Please put your heart into it,
will you?
我已经注意到你思想里
存在了某些犹豫不决的特性,
l've noticed a certain tentative quality
in your thinking,
犹如你的头脑被一大堆
棋盘之外的杂事
as if your mind were occupied
with issues
所占领了
就在你眼前.
other than those on the board
before you.
如此先入为主的成见
不但会削弱一个人的决断力,
Such preoccupation
not only weakens one's resolve,
还有远见.
but one's foresight as well.
这是任何竞赛中的致命弱点,
你必须同意这点,
A deadly failing in any match,
you must agree,
而且在这场特别的争夺战中,
损失会是相当惨重的灾难,
but in this particular contest,
quite disastrous,
尤其我们押上命做赌注,
as we play for grave stakes,
诸如此类的事
你不容置疑.
the likes of which
you have no doubt surmised.
把你的行动印在明天的报纸上.
Print your move in tomorrow's paper.
要不我就会替你印.
Or l will make it for you.
简直逼人太甚. 库珀,
我不会让你离开我视线之内的.
That tears it. Cooper,
I'm not Ietting you out of my sight.
哈里, 如果云顿想要杀我,
我早就死了.
Harry, if Windom wanted to kiII me,
I'd aIready be dead.
那是.
Yeah.
- 还是打电话给皮特吧.
- 对.
- Better get Pete on the horn.
- Right.
露西, 打电话给皮特·马爹利,
叫他马上赶过来这里.
Lucy, caII Pete MarteII,
get him over here right away.
然后打电话给报纸.
Then caII the paper.
查一下明天个人信息栏的
最迟截稿时间.
Find out the Iatest possibIe deadIine
for tomorrow's personaIs coIumn.
报纸和皮特, 收到.
我会按章办事.
Paper and Pete, got it.
l'll do it alphabetically.
她真美.
She was beautifuI.
我视她的爱如生命, 哈里.
She was the Iove of my Iife, Harry.
好的, 露西.
Okay, Lucy.
好的, 知道, 告诉哈里
我马上就到, 好吗?
Okay, yeah, just teII Harry
I'II be right there, okay?
好.
Right.
皮特.
Peter.
盐和胡椒粉.
SaIt and pepper.
马上来, 小松狮.
Coming right up, poodIe.
你们俩一起
就知道使坏.
You two bring out the worst
in each other.
- 哦, 皮特真是个人才.
- 一个宫廷小丑人才.
- Oh, Pete's a prince of a man.
- A court jester.
好了, 我要出去溜达了.
WeII, I've got to mosey.
再见, 可爱的帕卡族.
Goodbye, you sweet Packards.
噢, 凯萨琳.
Oh, Catherine.
凯萨琳, 我一直冀望
在你体内那股狂怒的暴风雨
Catherine, I'd aIways have hoped
that time and age wouId meIIow
会随着时间推移有所收敛.
that tempest raging inside you.
看着你们俩
十足一对傻帽似的
Watching you two act
Iike the Hardy Boys
我气就不打哪一处来.
aIways brings on stormy weather.
格斯伍的事怎样了?
What's happening with Ghostwood?
我和投资人谈过了,
会面都安排好了.
I taIked to the investors,
the meeting is set.
我明天就去巴黎.
I Ieave for Paris tomorrow.
噢, 伙伴回来了.
Oh, company.
亲爱的乔西...
Dear Josie...
我回家来了, 你想我么?
I'm home, did you miss me?
噢, 她看来惊喜过度了.
Oh, she Iooked surprised.
- 可怜的乔西.
- 噢, 再怎么说, 她还是有魅力的.
- Poor Josie.
- Oh, she has her charms, though.
是, 可惜不长久了.
Yes, but not for Iong.
进来.
Come in.
- 嗨, 哈里.
- 省点气吧, 汉克.
- Hi, Harry.
- Save it, Hank.
怎么啦? 心情不好?
今早上撞邪啦 ?
What happened? Did you get up on
the wrong side of the bed this morning?
我是违反了保释条例. 我泪流成河行了吧.
So I broke paroIe. Cry me a river.
你越过边境去加拿大.
You crossed the border into Canada.
你联系和安排毒贩
在死狗庄进行交易.
You consorted with the drug deaIers
at Dead Dog Farm.
你还意图谋杀.
You tried to kiII somebody.
我准备起诉你
企图谋杀里欧·强生.
I'm charging you with
the attempted murder of Leo Johnson.
好了, 我想里欧被枪击那晚
我正好在餐厅呢
WeII, I think it's safe to assume
that I was at the diner
这够保平安了吧.
the night that Leo was pIugged.
- 不信，欢迎你打电话去问--
- 我有目击证人.
- But you're weIcome to caII--
- I got a witness.
看见你
手里握着枪.
Puts you at the scene
with a gun in your hand.
哈里, 看来你这次
是动真格了,
Harry, you obviousIy seem serious
about this,
那么我打算提议来个交易.
so I'm going to propose a trade.
一个可以将杀害安德鲁·帕卡
的凶手逮捕
How about information
Ieading to the arrest
和定罪的
信息交换怎样?
and conviction
of Andrew Packard's murderer?
汉克·詹宁斯,
污点证人.
Hank Jennings,
witness for the prosecution.
没门.
No deaIs.
你是在告诉我
你对企图谋杀里欧·强生
You're teIIing me
you're more interested
这个案子，
比杀安德鲁·帕卡的重犯,
in the attempted murder
of Leo Johnson, feIon,
更感兴趣是吧?
than Andrew Packard?
你怎么对得住
你的选民?
How's that gonna sit
with your constituents?
你是彻底没救了, 汉克.
You're through, Hank.
我猜, 哈里, 这不太好.
My guess is, Harry, not too weII.
特别是一旦他们发现了
是谁暗算了安德鲁
EspeciaIIy once they find out
who pushed the button on Andrew
而你正好和她同床共枕.
and that you're sIeeping with her.
真糟糕, 不好意思了.
Gee, I'm sorry.
带他出去.
Get him out of here.
让他滚出去!
Get him out of here!
那个给我.
Give me that.
这是我们从你身上
取出来的子弹.
This is the buIIet we removed
from you.
而这一颗是从
那个死人的头骨的挖出来的.
This is the one that was excavated
from the dead man's skuII.
同一种子弹, 同一把枪, 同一个杀手.
我们去抓她吧.
Same buIIets, same gun, same kiIIer.
Let's go get her.
- 艾伯特, 稳住.
- 库,
- AIbert, hoId your horses.
- Coop,
我体谅你是极不情愿
逮捕你老友记的女人,
I appreciate any reIuctance you have
for busting your paI's oId Iady,
但这女人在你身上开了天窗
由你躺在那儿去死.
but the woman ventiIated you
and Ieft you for dead.
艾伯特, 我不是为了私人原因.
AIbert, I don't take it personaIIy.
那手套呢,
火药测试结果?
What about the gIoves,
the powder tests?
5点才有消息.
好了, 好了, 你不是傻子,
News at 5.
AII right, fine, you're not mad,
但这些如此类似的
枪伤像传染病一样
but there's an epidemic
of muItipIe gunshot wounds
反覆出现在这个女人所到之处.
她是个危险人物.
foIIowing this chick around.
She is a menace.
我会和她谈谈的.
I'II taIk to her.
也许她会认罪, 自首.
Maybe she'II confess, turn herseIf in.
她或许还会长出天使之翼
以后可以在马戏团表演呢.
Maybe she'II grow wings
and join the circus.
阮迪, 不重名嘉宾的名单
我已经做好了.
Randy, I've got a Iist
of aII our non-repeat guests.
我们要寄特别邀请卡给他们
请他们到大北方来.
We're gonna send them a speciaI
invitation to the Great Northern.
你的狂热和积极
的确让我热泪盈眶.
Your enthusiasm brings
a saIty tear to the eye.
只不过,
However,
我想你慢慢会发现
我对工作的要求不单只是
I think you wiII find my job requires
a IittIe more
衣冠整洁
和进取态度.
than a tight sweater
and a perky attitude.
阮迪, 我正在熟习业务呢.
Randy, I'm Iearning the business.
每周换一个不同的部门.
我不是非在你这儿不可的.
Every week a different department.
I don't want your job.
对, 我期待着
你最好只留在家里料理家事.
Yes, I Iook forward
to your stint in housekeeping.
这是今早送来给你的.
This came for you this morning.
祝你走运, 荷恩小姐.
你会需要它的.
Good Iuck, Miss Horne.
You'II need it.
嗨.
Hi.
- 我刚住进2了15房.
- 恭喜了.
- I just checked into Room 21 5.
- CongratuIations.
怪了, 前台的人告诉我
应该来找你.
Strange, they toId me at the front desk
I shouId taIk to you.
那我能帮你点什么?
What is it I can do for you?
抱歉, 还以为你正工作中呢.
Sorry, thought you were working.
我是在工作.
I am working.
我正工作呢, 看?
I'm working, see?
我看见了.
I see.
欧蕊.
Audrey.
- 荷恩?
- 随时为你效劳.
- Horne?
- At your service.
你能派个人
去机场吗?
CouId you send someone out
to the airport?
我这次出行
带了些很重的仪器.
I'm traveIing with some
heavy equipment this trip.
车里不够空间了.
Didn't have enough room in the van.
- 你乘的哪一班机?
- 我自己的.
- What fIight were you on?
- My own.
就外面那台喷气机.
应该不难找.
On the jet out there.
ShouIdn't be hard to find.
还有其他什么可以
帮到你吗, 洛克菲勒先生?
Is there anything eIse I can do
for you, Mr. RockefeIIer?
没了, 谢谢你.
No, thank you.
对了.
Yeah.
我有你的一张照片.
I have a picture of you.
你穿着一条紧身连衣小短裙,
带一条白围裙, 扎一条小猪尾辫子.
You're wearing a IittIe dirndI skirt, got
a white apron on, you have pigtaiIs.
无比可爱.
It's unbeIievabIy cute.
我不穿紧身连衣裙.
I don't wear dirndI.
那你以前穿.
You did then.
就在这儿.
大北方餐厅.
It was right here.
The Great Northern dining room.
我闭上双眼,
那情景几乎就在我眼前.
If I cIose my eyes,
I can aImost see it.
小欧蕊·荷恩就像快乐的海蒂精灵.
LittIe Audrey Horne as Heidi.
嗯, 总之, 令人难以忘怀.
WeII, anyway, it's unforgettabIe.
海蒂精灵.
Heidi.
我那时才10岁. 嘿!
I was 1 0. Hey!
谢谢你.
Thank you.
"救一个你爱的人.
''Save the one you Iove.
请出席今晚的天使集会
公路酒吧, 9:30."
PIease attend gathering of angeIs
tonight at the Road House, 9:30.''
纳丁?
Nadine?
小蜜糖, 回家来干嘛
放学了?
Honey, what are you doing home
from schooI?
还是你不舒服?
Are you feeIing poorIy?
别.
Don't.
别什么?
Don't what?
噢, 小艾艾. 我们得谈谈了.
Oh, Eddie. We have to taIk.
好.
Okay.
迈克和我相爱了.
Mike and I are in Iove.
- 相爱?
- 我希望你不会伤心.
- In Iove?
- I hope you're not hurt.
我不愿让这世上的任何事
而伤害到你.
I wouIdn't wanna hurt you
for anything in the worId.
坦白说吧, 你不得不信.
Honest, you have to beIieve that.
迈克和我, 在去参加摔跤比赛的旅途上,
But Mike and I, on that wrestIing trip,
我们一起渡过了
一个充满魔力的夜晚.
we had the most
magicaI night together.
整晚?
AII night?
嗯, 你和诺玛不也是吗.
WeII, you and Norma did it.
那好, 那很公平.
WeII, that's fair.
那, 这是什么意思呢?
So, what's this mean?
小艾艾.
Eddie.
我们不妨直说了吧.
We have to caII a spade a spade.
我们完了.
We're breaking up.
小艾艾,
Eddie,
对不起了.
I'm so sorry.
乔西, 我想你对我坦白
在西雅图到底发生了什么.
Josie, I want you to IeveI with me
about what happened in SeattIe.
我告诉过你了.
I toId you.
我还要
说几遍啊?
How many times
do I have to say it?
我从乔纳森手上逃跑了
就在机场那儿
I escaped from Jonathan
in the airport
再之后他发生了什么
我就不知道了.
and I don't know
what happened to him after that.
你知道吗
我立刻就能逮捕你?
Do you understand
I couId arrest you right now?
我是以哈里朋友的身份来的.
I came here as a friend of Harry's.
现在, 我不知道他
在你心目中占什么地位,
Now, I don't know what pIace
he occupies in your heart,
但我知道你欠他的.
but I do know that you own his.
我只想你能有个机会
自己向他解释.
I wouId think you'd Iike a chance
to expIain yourseIf to him.
请你走吧.
PIease go.
这是终点了, 乔西.
别无选择.
This is the end of it, Josie.
There are no other options.
我想你9点在
警察局出现.
I want you at the station house
by 9:00.
要不我就来找你.
Or I come and find you.
噢, 乔西,
我刚看见库珀探员走了.
Oh, Josie,
I just saw Agent Cooper Ieave.
是来做社会访问吗?
Was this a sociaI caII?
亲爱的, 你脸色难看极了.
Dear, you Iook awfuI.
一切都还好吧?
Is everything aII right?
- 我觉得不太舒服.
- 哦, 我为你难过.
- I don't feeI very weII.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
我希望我带来的消息好些.
I wish I had better news.
我代表你的利益
再和埃卡先生谈过一次了.
I've spoken to Mr. Eckhardt again
on your behaIf.
他还没
完全和我达成共识,
WhiIe he's not
entireIy unsympathetic,
他坚持要单独见你.
he does insist on seeing you aIone.
今晚.
Tonight.
他会杀了我的.
He'II kiII me.
老实跟你说了吧,
To teII you the truth,
我最大的担忧是
当他发现安德鲁
my biggest worry is
what he's going to do
原来还活生生时
他会怎么做呢.
when he finds out
that Andrew is aIive.
难道埃卡先生不会觉得
你已经背叛他了吗?
Won't Mr. Eckhardt think
that you've betrayed him?
当然了, 你可以告诉他
你没有.
But of course, you can teII him
that you didn't.
毕竟, 你真的以为
安德鲁死了.
After aII, you did actuaIIy think
that Andrew was dead.
噢, 不.
Oh, no.
我不知道. 我不知道.
I don't know. I don't know.
或许你能帮我.
我想我快发疯了.
Maybe you can heIp me.
I think I'm going mad.
你早晚都要
直接面对
You wiII simpIy have to face
Mr. Eckhardt
埃卡先生的.
sooner or Iater.
告诉他真相就好了.
TeII him the truth.
把你想的都告诉他.
TeII him whatever you want.
然后祈求他会相信你.
Just pray that he beIieves you.
噢, 找到了.
Oh, there they are.
没人接. 他肯定在来的路上.
No answer. He must be on his way.
谢谢, 波比.
Thanks, Bobby.
瞧, 为什么不加入我们呢?
Look, why don't you join us?
- 什么?
- 是啊.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
要知道, 董事会议
无非就是
You know, board meetings are usuaIIy
nothing more than a gathering
集合众智,
of seIf-minded individuaIs,
多一个人
多一分力.
each more intent
than the other on financiaI gain.
不要了, 谢谢你.
No, thank you.
但今天...
But today...
今天有些局面将会
完全不同.
Today is going to be
something compIeteIy different.
我迟到了吗? 猛将来啦, 本,
看看你. 你好吗?
Am I Iate? Hot dog, Ben,
Iook at you. How are you?
- 你真是贵客临门啊.
- 看你说的.
- You are a sight for sore eyes.
- Look who's taIking.
- 你觉得我们的服务还行吧?
- 顶级.
- We taking good care of you?
- The best.
我的行李到了.
谢谢你, 欧蕊.
My Iuggage arrived.
Thank you, Audrey.
- 你们俩已经见过了?
- 简单见过了.
- You two have met?
- BriefIy.
庄·爵斯廷·维乐.
John Justice WheeIer.
以前做建筑的.
Used to be in construction.
- 靠自己出人头地.
- 真不错.
- Came up the hard way.
- How nice.
你还记得我弟弟杰里?
You remember my brother Jerry?
- 那就是杰里. 噢, 我的天.
- 嗨, 杰克.
- That is Jerry. Oh, my God.
- Hi, Jack.
这是我的行政助理,
波比·布里格斯.
And this is my executive assistant,
Bob Briggs.
- 波.
- 嘿, 好吗?
- Bob.
- Hey, what's up?
- 高兴认识你.
- 为什么你们不坐下谈呢?
- PIeasure.
- Why don't you aII just take a seat?
我邀请维乐先生
加入我们的董事会.
I've asked Mr. WheeIer
to join us on the board.
几年前,
我在他身上,
Years ago,
I made an investment in him,
投资了一点小钱,
a pittance,
而他却因此构建了一个王国.
which he buiIt into an empire.
现在, 我再也贷不到款了,
Now, I don't take any credit,
但我相信杰克
but I beIieved in Jack
即使当他还是个一文不名
的小子时.
even when he was a IocaI boy
pounding naiIs.
我现在也请他相信我
帮回我一个忙.
I've asked him to return the favor
and beIieve in me now.
本, 你在考验我
到底有多谦逊.
Ben, you're testing
my weII-worn modesty.
好了, 足可以这样说,
AII right, suffice to say,
荷恩企业公司
已经陷入困境了.
Horne Industries Incorporated
have faIIen on hard times.
锯木厂,
The miII,
格斯伍的土地, 现在全部
为凯萨琳·马爹利独家拥有.
the Ghostwood Iands, are now
soIeIy owned by Catherine MarteII.
我们不羡慕她,
毕竟, 锯木厂从前至今, 原本就是她的.
We don't begrudge her,
the miII was and is, after aII, hers.
所以,
So,
理所当然回转到她手里
in spite of these reversaIs
那么在撕下成功的
外衣后,
and stripped of aII the trappings
of success,
我们还剩下什么呢?
what are we Ieft with?
人性.
The human spirit.
一个人能施与别人的
What is the greatest gift
最大的恩赐
是什么呢?
that one human being can give
to another?
是未来.
The future.
我将赠与你们的...
I give you...
...就是这小松鼬.
...the IittIe pine weaseI.
被发现只在我们三县地区才有的品种,
Found onIy in our tri-county area,
快濒临绝种了.
it is nearIy extinct.
它们烤起来一定无比美味.
They're incredibIe roasted.
根据环境影响
报告,
According to an environmentaI
impact report,
仅存的几只松鼬
将会被
what few pine weaseIs remain
wiII be aII but wiped out
发展格斯伍的帕卡计划
赶尽杀绝.
with the Packard pIans
for Ghostwood deveIopment.
所以你想拯救松鼬吗?
So you wanna save the weaseI?
不, 波比.
No, Bobby.
不单只是松鼬.
Not just the weaseI.
而是人人皆知的生活.
But Iife as we know it.
我要双峰镇
I want Twin Peaks
在这场空前巨大的
to remain unspoiIed
环境大屠杀中
完好无损的保存下来.
in an era
of vast environmentaI carnage.
因此，直到幸运之轮回转
和我们能再次出击之前
So we bIock Catherine's deveIopment
untiI the wheeI turns
我们要阻止凯瑟琳的发展.
and we get another shot.
简直太有才了, 本. 简直太有才了.
That's briIIiant, Ben. That's briIIiant.
我计划好了
I pIan to fight
我将利用一切可能的武器
在这片格斯伍发展的
this Ghostwood deveIopment
on every ground
每一寸土地上战斗到底.
and with every avaiIabIe weapon.
这小松鼬...
The IittIe pine weaseI...
...即将成为
一个家喻户晓的名字.
...is about to become
a househoId word.
之后呢?
Then what?
然后我会考虑
Then I am considering
去参议院竞选.
a run for the Senate.
谢谢你.
Thank you.
安妮, 没问题.
我有空房.
Annie, it's no probIem.
I've got pIenty of room.
你就乘下一趟车来吧, 好吗?
我等你.
You just get on the next bus, okay?
And I'II be waiting.
噢, 蜜糖儿, 别哭.
Oh, honey, don't cry.
很快就没事了.
It's gonna be aII right.
等会儿见.
I'II see you soon.
我也爱你.
I Iove you too.
再见.
Bye.
- 你姐姐要来了?
- 明天.
- So your sister coming?
- Tomorrow.
上帝, 你得做什么
才能离开修道院呢?
God, what do you have to do
to get out of a convent?
就这样走啊, 又不是监狱.
You just Ieave, it's not a prison.
我听起来就像监狱.
没电视, 没男友.
Sounds Iike prison to me.
No TV, no boyfriends.
你知道吗, 她小的时候,
我就总在想
You know, when she was IittIe,
I aIways used to think
安妮是从
另一个时空里来的.
that Annie was
from another pIace and time.
我觉得，在某种程度上来说
修道院倒是挺适合她的.
I guess the convent has been good
for her in a way.
很难想像她出来以后会是怎样.
Hard to imagine her out in the worId.
噢, 看, 有东西给你.
Oh, Iook, here's something for you.
- 谁的?
- 我想是刚刚坐那儿的人留下的吧.
- Who from?
- I guess who was ever sitting there.
看这个.
Look at this.
"山轻吻, 浪轻拥.
''Mountains kiss, waves cIasp.
鲜花, 阳光, 月色,
这一切都是, 汝之吻."
FIower, sunIight, the moonbeams,
is aII this, thou kiss.''
无厘头.
None of this makes sense.
"拯救你爱的人.
''Save the one you Iove.
请出席今晚的天使集会
公路酒吧, 9:30."
PIease attend a gathering of the angeIs
tonight at the Road House, 9:30.''
听起来像是恶作剧,
Sounds intriguing in a way,
而且感觉挺危险的.
but it sounds dangerous.
我想知道是谁拿来的.
I wonder who this is from.
诺玛·詹宁斯, 在过去的20年里
我每天都爱着你
Norma Jennings, I've Ioved you
every day for the past 20 years
每夜都梦见你.
and I dream about you every night.
我们是时候在一起了.
It's time for us to be together.
你愿意嫁给我吗?
WiII you marry me?
- 艾德?
- 我们应得幸福快乐.
- Ed?
- We deserve to be happy.
终于轮到我们了, 宝贝.
It's our turn, baby.
我整夜拥她在怀
All night long l held her in my arms
只为了保护她
远离深雾般, 深雾般的晨露
Just to keep her
From the foggy, foggy dew
干的好, 伙计.
Good job, feIIa.
好孩子.
Good boy.
再多做几根, 我们就去吃饭了.
Just a few more, and then we'II eat.
飞向我的胸膛,
刺进我色彩斑斓的秋天,
Fly to my breast,
Pierce me in colors autumnal,
只对我倾诉爱意.
speak to me only of love.
里欧, 你的训练
还未完成.
Leo, you have
an incompIete education.
比如,
在野外生存?
For instance,
survivaI in the wiIderness?
一个关乎你性命的重大课题,
我的朋友.
A reIevant issue in your Iife,
my friend.
现在, 接着来进行
实践教学.
Now, this comes under the heading
of practicaI instruction.
我希望你留心听讲.
I hope you've been paying attention.
大自然是残酷无情的.
Nature is crueI.
这也算是一课吧.
This is aIso a Iesson.
嗨, 蜜糖儿.
Hi, honey.
你现在感觉如何?
How are you feeIing?
噢, 好极了, 现在你来了.
Oh, great, now that you're here.
汉克, 我来这里
是要求你离婚的.
Hank, I came here
to ask you for a divorce.
好, 让我先说,
我不怪你.
WeII, first Iet me say,
I don't bIame you.
你给了我第二次机会
但我搞砸了.
You gave me a second chance
and I bIew it.
我不知道
我为啥这样自我毁灭,
I don't know
why I'm so seIf-destructive,
但我能看到
but I can see
我越来越会分轻重了.
that that's my priority in getting weII.
我有很多事可以干.
I got a Iot of work to do.
事实上, 我决定
In fact, I decided
尝试去做治疗.
I'm gonna try to go into therapy.
我再也不会这样了.
I don't wanna be Iike this anymore.
那会非常有意思, 汉克.
That's very interesting, Hank.
但我得继续过我的生活.
But I have to get on with my Iife.
我知道.
I know.
我知道你要过活.
I know you do.
我只是想你过的快乐.
I just want you to be happy.
谢谢你了.
Thank you.
我想你帮我最后一个忙.
I want you to do me one Iast favor.
我要你帮我
离开这儿.
I want you to heIp me
get out of here.
如果他们把我送回监狱,
我会死的.
If they send me back to prison,
I'II die.
告诉警长
里欧·强生中枪那晚
TeII the sheriff
that I was at the restaurant
我在
餐馆里呆着.
the night
that Leo Johnson was shot.
我当时正在回家的路上.
我不能证明, 但你可以.
I was on my way home.
I can't prove it, but you can.
不要再撒谎了, 汉克.
No more Iies, Hank.
这不是撒谎,
这可是救我的命啊.
It's not Iying,
it's trying to save my Iife.
不.
No.
你想我死在这儿, 诺玛.
You're kiIIing me here, Norma.
别怪到我头上.
你怎么敢这样.
Don't bIame this on me.
Don't you dare.
是艾德吧?
Is it Ed?
那个你要投怀送抱的人?
Is that who you're running to?
好.
Okay.
那就来个交易.
Then here's the deaI.
你给我不在场证据
我就跟你离婚.
You give me my aIibi
and I give you your divorce.
我可不是到这儿来
和你谈判的.
I didn't come here
to negotiate with you.
就这样了, 一切都结束了.
This is it, it's over.
好.
Fine.
随你吧.
Go ahead.
你是他的妓女, 诺玛.
You're his whore, Norma.
我宁愿做他的妓女
也不愿做你妻子.
I'd rather be his whore
than your wife.
诺玛!
Norma!
现在, 可以用4到5个不同的方法
来走这步棋,
Now, there are four or five
different ways of doing this thing,
而且各有长处.
and they aII have their virtues.
我还记得1914年，在圣彼得堡,
I remember CapabIanca and Lasker,
卡柏布兰卡对战拉斯卡--
St. Petersburg, 1 91 4--
- 皮特.
- 是.
- Pete.
- Yeah.
我们只有五分钟.
We've onIy got five minutes.
好吧.
AII right.
- 露西.
- 警长?
- Lucy.
- Sheriff?
打电话给报社.
Get the Gazette on the phone.
叫他们的个人信息栏目部
先别下班. 我们还需要多点时间.
TeII them not to cIose out
the personaIs. We need more time.
- 报社.
- 好了.
- The Gazette.
- Okay.
就是这个了.
That's it.
保证能导致
好些个不眠之夜了.
Guaranteed to cause
some sIeepIess nights.
这样他就不能
吃掉棋盘上的任何一只棋.
As Iong as he can't remove
another piece from the board.
他不能吧.
至少5、6步之内.
He can't do it.
Not at Ieast for five, six more moves.
反正，他还是会杀人的.
Maybe he'II kiII anyway.
- 或许这只能挫败一下他的锐气.
- 我不这么认为, 哈里.
- Maybe it'II just frustrate him.
- I don't think so, Harry.
厄尔很乖张的
面子对他至关重要.
EarIe has a perverse sense of honor
about these things.
我从没听过一个人
会按章法杀人的.
I never heard of a man
who murdered by the ruIes.
库?
Coop?
艾伯特.
AIbert.
干的好, 皮特.
Good work, Pete.
是这样的, 开门见山吧.
Here it is, straight up.
我核对过袭击你的那把枪上
的火药残余物
I got a match on the gun that
whacked you with the powder residue
和乔西·帕卡手套上残留的一样.
on Josie Packard's gIoves.
西雅图警方还
找到了一个目击证人
SeattIe poIice have aIso
come up with an eyewitness
确认就是乔西
在发现尸体的地方下车的.
who positiveIy ID'd Josie Ieaving
the car where they found the stiff.
如果你还不打算逮捕这个婊子的话,
If you ain't gonna bust this bitch,
- 我会把这当作是私人原因--
- 艾伯特, 我能处理这事儿.
- I wouId consider it a personaI--
- AIbert, I can handIe it.
我想你刚已经处理了.
I think you just did.
进来.
Come in.
我猜想
你仍喜欢香槟酒的味道.
I assume
you stiII have a taste for bubbIy.
我们在一起时
不知干掉了多少瓶.
We've kiIIed enough bottIes
in our time.
为自始.
To beginnings.
至终, 还有为能洞悉不同的智慧
干一杯.
And endings, and the wisdom
to know the difference.
我对不起你, 安德鲁.
I am sorry, Andrew.
的确，我刚开始是恨你.
I hated you at first, of course.
再正常不过的反应.
PerfectIy normaI response.
但当我的愤怒渐渐平息,
As my anger diminished,
我就回想起埃卡总有办法
去说服别人做任何事.
I recaIIed that Eckhardt has a way
of persuading peopIe to do anything.
- 肯定是他的主意.
- 对.
- It was his idea, of course.
- Yes.
是他让我干的.
He made me do it.
他还说你从没爱过我.
And he said you never Ioved me.
你娶我只是
为了报复他.
You just married me
to get back at him.
那不是真的,
我真的非常爱你.
That's not true,
I did Iove you very much.
当然了,
那已经成为过去了.
Of course,
the same cannot be said for you.
别, 乔西,
PIease, Josie,
我们之间不要再互相欺骗了.
Iet there be no more Iies between us.
既然你做了.
现在就得付出代价.
You had a job to do and you did it.
Now you're paying the price.
做任何事都是有后果的,
我亲爱的.
Every action has its consequence,
my dear.
警察已经离你很近了.
如果你再不行动,
The poIice are cIosing in.
If you don't take action,
你今晚就要在牢房里过夜了.
you'II be sIeeping in a jaiI ceII tonight.
我能做什么? 请救救我.
What can I do? PIease heIp me.
你必须去见埃卡.
You must see Eckhardt.
或许你们永远在一起
才是有意义的.
Perhaps you were meant
to be together aII aIong.
我相信他是真的爱你.
I'm sure he truIy Ioves you.
他不知道我还活着.
他能带你离开这个国家.
He doesn't know I'm aIive.
He can get you out of this country.
去找他吧, 乔西.
Go to him, Josie.
马上.
Now.
安德鲁.
Andrew.
我们不会再见了.
We won't speak again.
嗨.
Hi.
真美啊.
It's beautifuI.
我想去些
我们从没去过的地方.
I wanted us to go somepIace
we've never been before.
来吧.
Come on.
警方怎么处理?
How did it go with the poIice?
他们问了无数个
我都不知道答案的问题.
They asked a miIIion questions
that I didn't know the answers to.
但有一个我知道
我想知道了这一个已经足够了.
But the ones I did
must have been enough.
伊夫林将会被审判
而我将是证人.
EveIyn's gonna stand triaI
and I'II be a witness.
你没戴那戒指.
You're not wearing the ring.
我知道你和伊夫林的事了.
I know about you and EveIyn.
如果你恨我
我不会怪你.
I wouIdn't bIame you
if you hated me.
詹姆斯,
我了解你的感受.
James,
I know what you were feeIing.
我也有同样的感受.
I was feeIing it too.
只不过让伊夫林有机可乘罢了.
EveIyn just took advantage of it.
嗯, 我本来知道
那是错误的.
WeII, it was wrong
and I shouId've known that.
瞧, 你对发生的事感到沮丧
那很正常,
Look, it's okay for you to feeI bad
about what happened to you,
但我不想你为我
感到沮丧.
but I don't want you to feeI bad
for me.
如果我们可以从头再来...
If we couId just start over again...
请你跟我回家吧.
PIease come home with me.
现在，我还不能.
I can't. Not right now.
你是对的. 你该离开.
You're right. You shouId go.
但你怎么办?
But what about you?
不用再为我担心了.
Can't worry about me anymore.
发生了那么多可怕的事
我都
I've been a part
of aII the horribIe things
身在其中.
that have happened.
现在，我打算
融入新生活了.
I wanna be a part
of something good now.
詹姆斯, 走吧.
James, go.
给自己足够的时间.
Take aII the time you need.
我爱你.
I Iove you.
我会想你想到发疯的.
I'm gonna miss you Iike crazy.
但你去奔吧
But you'II go away
然后带着
好故事回来.
and you'II come back
with great stories.
主角不会再是劳拉
马蒂或者伊夫林了.
And none of them are gonna be
about Laura or Maddy or EveIyn.
我会在这儿等你.
And I'II be here.
- 跟我走吧.
- 不.
- Come with me.
- No.
好, 那, 我会回来, 我保证.
WeII, then, I'II come back, I promise.
来了.
Coming.
- 皮特, 我要见乔西.
- 进来说.
- Pete, I need to see Josie.
- Come on in.
- 我想她已经走了.
- 就是, 相当奇怪.
- I think she's gone out.
- Yes, it's rather odd.
她二话不说
就把我的车开走了.
She took my car
without saying a word.
对, 她和我说过
大北方.
WeII, she toId me
the Great Northern.
噢, 她说过吗? 嗯,
她还拿了很多她的东西走.
Oh, did she? WeII,
she took a Iot of things with her.
我不知道她打算去哪儿.
I don't know where she was going.
但我可以说
她会计划停留一阵子的.
But I'd say she was pIanning
to stay a whiIe.
她还说了其它什么, 皮特?
What eIse did she say, Pete?
哦, 她打算去见
一个老朋友.
WeII, that she was going to see
an oId friend.
是谁?
Who?
警长, 对我们大家来说
知道乔西的真面目
Sheriff, I suppose it's been very hard
on aII of us
是件相当难受的事.
Iearning the truth about Josie.
凯萨琳.
Catherine.
到底是谁?
Who?
埃卡. 托马斯·埃卡.
Eckhardt. Thomas Eckhardt.
可怜的人.
Poor man.
到大堂, 谢谢.
Lobby, pIease.
托马斯.
Thomas.
我们又见面了.
We meet again.
我不相信鬼魂的.
I don't beIieve in ghosts.
真可惜, 鬼魂其实是个很有趣的概念.
Pity, it's an appeaIing notion.
一个从坟墓回归的
恐怖魅影.
The return of the grisIy phantom
from the grave.
你要真闹鬼了, 那才好呢.
You deserve haunting, to be sure.
看真点, 托马斯.
Look cIoser, Thomas.
我还活着.
I'm aIive.
怎么回事?
How?
猜猜看. 不明摆着的吗.
Guess. It's reaIIy very simpIe.
乔西.
Josie.
她亲自警告我离开的.
She warned me off herseIf.
不忍心看着自己
心爱的丈夫死去.
CouIdn't bear to see
her beIoved husband perish.
再现实点说吧, 我想,
Or more reaIisticaIIy, I suppose,
她觉得
这样对她更有利.
she feIt there was
some advantage to be gained.
她背叛了我.
She betrayed me.
我们都被耍了.
We're aII famiIiar with betrayaI.
乔西是我的. 她属于我.
Josie is mine. She beIongs to me.
噢, 托马斯,
爱使人心碎.
Oh, Thomas,
Iove wiII break your heart.
幸好, 很久以前, 我就对此失去兴趣了.
HappiIy, Iong ago, I Iost interest.
但乔西的恐惧性
常规失心疯.
But Josie Ioses her heart
with aIarming reguIarity.
让她在所有人当中, 偏偏选中了那个土警长.
The IocaI sheriff, of aII peopIe.
- 我会处理那事的.
- 我对此毋庸置疑.
- I have taken care of that.
- I don't doubt it.
有时我真的很怀疑
我们的乔西是否
Sometimes I wonder
if our Josie
故意的要去做这些
扭曲的事.
does these twisted things
deIiberateIy.
你说呢?
Don't you?
作为你
已故的朋友,
As someone
who was once your friend,
我是特意回来给你提个醒.
I come back with a warning.
乔西正来找你呢,
千万小心咯.
Josie is coming back to you,
be very carefuI.
我一向小心谨慎.
I'm aIways carefuI.
那好, 我们到了, 大堂.
WeII, here we are, the Iobby.
我要回到楼下
车房去了.
I'II be going back down
to the garage.
我的复活还是
个无人知晓的秘密.
My resurrection remains
a weII-kept secret.
托马斯.
Thomas.
再见.
Bye.
我知道我还有好多要学习.
I know that I have a Iot to Iearn.
杰克,
Jack,
你将是我的老师.
you shaII be my teacher.
把我当作是一本打开的书,
Think of me as an open book,
你可以在这干净的页面上
随意书写.
upon whose virgin pages
you shaII scribe.
你没事吧?
You okay?
那, 维乐先生,
你到底是做什么的?
So, Mr. WheeIer,
what is it exactIy you do do?
首先, 请叫我杰克吧.
First off, caII me Jack, pIease.
我买进破产，经营失败的企业.
I buy bankrupt, faiIing businesses.
我会重整它们的资源,
让它们回到正常运作的轨道
I streamIine them,
bring them back up to speed
然后，通常会卖掉它们.
and then usuaIIy seII them.
利润可观啊.
At a substantiaI profit.
但是, 我要加上一点,
But not, I shouId add,
要在得到重要的环境特许
前提下进行.
before making significant
environmentaI concessions.
不止, 当杰克完成后,
垃圾要改道而行, 空气...
No, when Jack is finished,
the waste is rerouted, the air...
空气会更亲新.
The air is cIeaner.
而人们也更快乐了.
And the peopIe happier.
本, 你把我说的
像圣诞老人.
Ben, you make me sound
Iike Santa CIaus.
我只是一个商人, 仅此而已.
I'm a businessman, that's aII.
请恕我失陪了,
厨师刚要拿刀刺杰里呢.
You'II have to excuse me,
the chef just tried to stab Jerry.
孩子们，你们继续吧.
You kids carry on.
留心了.
Pay attention.
那, 维乐先生,
So, Mr. WheeIer,
我们算是哪一个呢,
破产还是经营不善?
which is it,
are we bankrupt or just faiIing?
我是来帮老朋友一个忙.
还有是杰克.
I came to do an oId friend a favor.
And it's Jack.
我爸爸的朋友
比松鼬还珍稀.
My father's friends are rarer
than the pine weaseI.
那, 让我们这样说好了
WeII, Iet's just say
本曾经是我
一个非常要好的朋友.
that Ben was once
a very good friend to me.
那么你来就是要
把我们带回到正常运作轨道咯.
So you came back
to bring us aII up to speed.
你是圣诞老人, 维乐先生.
我最好把我的袜子先挂起来.
You are Santa CIaus, Mr. WheeIer.
I'd better hang up my stocking.
你不太喜欢我,
对吗, 欧蕊?
You don't Iike me very much,
do you, Audrey?
反正我没意见.
I don't have an opinion either way.
但如果你有呢?
But if you did?
如果我有,
If I did,
我会说，这么多年以来
荷恩家族一直把自己管理的好好的
I'd say that the Hornes have managed
to take care of themseIves just fine
远比你看起来的价值重要.
for more years than you can count.
尽管我们可能看起来
很绝望的样子,
And desperate
though we may seem,
在可见的将来
这情形还会持续下去.
wiII probabIy continue to do so
in the foreseeabIe future.
那倒是.
Indeed.
你之前都去哪儿了?
Where have you been aII this time?
我指, 你不是忙着去拯救
寡妇和孤儿，就是忙着要把我们的
I mean, when you weren't busy
rescuing widows and orphans
世界改造的更美好，适宜居住
但除此之外呢.
and making our worId
a better pIace to Iive in.
在天涯海角.
The far corners of the earth.
我告诉你, 外面的世界很精彩,
欧蕊.
I teII you, it's gIorious out there,
Audrey.
但再什么说, 回到家的感觉还真好.
AII in aII, it's good to be home.
我才18.
I'm onIy 1 8.
还有，鸡蛋的价格
究竟怎么回事?
And what exactIy does that have to do
with the price of eggs?
没事了.
Nothing.
上帝, 看时间都过了.
我还有个预约呢.
God, Iook at the time.
I have an appointment.
- 你能转告我父亲吗?
- 当然了.
- CouId you teII my father?
- Sure.
好的. 再见.
Okay. See you.
再见.
Bye.
回见, 杰克.
I'II see you Iater, Jack.
回见, 欧蕊.
I'II see you, Audrey.
- 雪莉? 嗨.
- 嗨. 你好吗?
- SheIIy? Hi.
- Hi. How are you?
还好. 你过得怎样?
I'm okay. How are you doing?
就过日子呗. 来一口?
You know Iife. Drag?
你在等詹姆斯?
Are you waiting for James?
不.
No.
其实，我是收到这些怪字条才来的.
ActuaIIy I got this reaIIy weird note.
有人想我
来这见他们.
Somebody wants me
to meet them here.
怪吧?
That strange?
那就怪了, 看我有什么.
That is strange, Iook what I have.
看来我们好像都有事
要一起谈了.
It Iooks Iike we aII have something
to taIk about.
刚好.
It fits.
看那山峰高耸入云,
犹如波涛延绵不断
See the mountains kiss high heaven,
And the waves clasp one another
没有一朵姐妹花会被宽恕
如果它鄙视它的兄弟
No sister-flower would be forgiven
lf it disdain'd its brother
阳光紧扣着大地,
月光则亲吻着大海--
And the sunlight clasps the earth,
And the moonbeams kiss the sea--
如果汝不吻我,
这世间一切的甜蜜之事价值何在呢?
What is all this sweet work worth,
lf thou kiss not me?
- 我只能说.
- 这太奇怪了.
- This is weird.
- I'II say.
我是库珀. 是的, 凯萨琳.
Cooper here. Yes, Catherine.
不, 不, 我刚回来不久.
No, no, I was just on my way over.
她在这儿?
She's here?
在托马斯·埃卡的房间.
Thomas Eckhardt's suite.
我知道了.
I see.
救命!
HeIp!
- 救命啊.
- 我爱你.
- PIease heIp.
- I Iove you.
- 别!
- 乔西, 别这样. 看在上帝的份上--
- No!
- Josie, pIease. For God's sake--
别碰我. 别摸我!
别伤害我.
Don't touch me. Don't touch me!
Don't hurt me.
你给我站住.
Stay where you are.
他想杀我.
He tried to kiII me.
你也打算这样形容我吗,
乔西? 我也想杀你?
Is that what you'II say about me,
Josie? That I tried to kiII you?
那乔纳森呢?
What about Jonathan?
难道他也想杀你吗?
Did he try to kiII you too?
他要抓我回去.
He was taking me back.
你为什么要开枪打我, 乔西?
Why did you shoot me, Josie?
因为你的到来.
Because you came here.
我就知道会有这么一天的.
I knew this day was going to come.
我不要坐牢. 我不可以.
I'm not going to jaiI. I can't.
把枪放下, 乔西.
Put it down, Josie.
- 哈里.
- 把枪放下!
- Harry.
- Put it down!
哈里, 原谅我吧.
Harry, forgive me.
我从来没想过要伤害你的.
I never meant to hurt you.
乔西. 乔西.
Josie. Josie.
乔西.
Josie.
她死了.
She's dead.
乔西.
Josie.
库, 死鬼乔西到底发生什么了?
Coop, what happened to dead Josie?
哦, 乔西.
Oh, Josie.